(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T10:27:25.446547",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
誰にも愛されてない
I'm not loved by anyone at all,
自己中が好きじゃないけれどさ
and I don't really like being selfish, but...
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
今日も明日も未来も作ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for creating today, tomorrow, and my future too!
時々ガス代払えない
Sometimes I can't pay the gas bill,
アイフォンがバキバキ
my iPhone is completely shattered,
回しても推しが出てこない
and my oshi still won't drop when I pull.
毎日がEveryday
Every single day is everyday—
すぐに落ち込んで
Getting depressed right away
泣いちゃうことだって赤ちゃんじゃ仕方ないね
and crying just can't be helped since I'm a baby, right?
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
言えんなんて言わないもん！
I don't say things like "I wanna die"!
ありあまってらる感情なんて 映えやしない芝居のいらない
I don't need overflowing emotions or unphotogenic acts.
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
嫌いだって少ないもん！
I barely even hate anything!
うつりだしてうるさい 飽き性 うるさい 待てない もう知らない
Fading in, so annoying, fickle, annoying, can't wait, I'm done!
明日の予定だったりさ
Things like tomorrow's schedule
今月の生活だとか
or this month's living expenses—
気にしすぎてマジ病む
worrying about them too much makes me genuinely sick.
誰にも愛されてない 自己中が好きじゃない
Not loved by anyone, and I don't like being selfish,
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
but I'm not a mental health case!
時々ガス代払えない
Sometimes I can't pay the gas bill,
アイフォンがバキバキ
my iPhone is completely shattered,
回しても推しが出てこない
and my oshi still won't drop when I pull.
毎日がEveryday
Every single day is everyday—
すぐに落ち込んで
Getting depressed right away,
たまになんて逃げ出すことだって
and even wanting to run away sometimes...
ポンコツじゃ無理もんの おれ？
as a useless person, that's impossible for... me?
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
涙なんか見せないもん！
I won't show any tears!
瀬戸際だからほらだらだらと
We're on the edge, so look, just slacking off
緩く毎日を生きてるだけ
and living lazily day by day is all I do.
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
ポンとなんて言わないもん！
I won't say things like "I'm done"!
ありあまってらる感情なんて 映えやしない芝居もしもいらない
I don't need overflowing emotions or unphotogenic acts at all.
私メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a mental health case!
裏腹だって少ないもん！
My contradictions are pretty minimal too!
ぐずりだしてうざい 嫌い うるさい 待てない もう知らない
Whining, annoying, hateful, noisy, can't wait, I'm done!
もう一回お願いします！
One more time, please!
あーもう嫌 今も走る
Ah, I hate it, still running
止まってしまえばいい もう無理無理無理無理
It'd be fine if I just stopped. No more, no more!
やめてやめてやめてやめて 息止まれ 声枯らせ
Stop, stop, stop, stop! Stop breathing, lose your voice
もっと死ね 狂え狂え狂え狂え
Die more! Go mad, go mad, go mad, go mad!
なんか少しそう ケチな人生
Somehow a bit, yeah, a stingy life
溜まりに溜まって生きてた 逃げ出すことだって
Living with piled-up stress, even running away
パンクじゃ 何もないね
Is a punk move, nothing to it
私メンヘラじゃないもん
I'm not a mental case!
涙なんか見せないもん
I won't show any tears!
筋がないからほら だらだらと緩く毎日を生きてるだけ
Since there's no spine, look, I'm just living lazily every day
私メンヘラじゃないもん
I'm not a mental case!
掃き溜めじゃ言わないもん
I won't say it's a cesspool!
ありあまって揺らる感情だって 栄えあるプライドもいらない
Even overflowing, shaking emotions, I don't need glorious pride
メンヘラじゃないもん
I'm not a mental case!
裏のことって少ないもん 擦り出してる罪悪感嫌い
There's little hidden behind it, I hate grinding out guilt
うるさい待てだれも知らない
Noisy, wait, nobody knows
好きぴの好きぴだったりさ 友達いない悩みには
Crushes liking someone else, or having no friends
ずっとストロングしか勝たん
Strong Zero is always the only winner
誰にも焦らせてない自分
Myself, not rushing anyone
が、好きじゃないけれども
Though I don't like it...
私メンヘラじゃないもん
I'm not a mental case!
永遠チェーンソー！
Eternal chainsaw!
救急ベイビー ひやおお 回せ回せじゃん
Emergency baby, hiyooo, spin, spin, yeah!
右から来るぞ、気をつけろ！
Something's coming from the right, watch out!
うわあ！
Whoa!
お前、俺より出で立ちじゃねえぞ。おいおいおいおい！
You're standing out more than me! Hey hey hey hey!
こっち行くぞ。
Let's go this way.
どこ行った？
Where'd it go?
あれ？さっき戻るころ
Huh? Just a moment ago...
あれ？おらん。
Huh? Not here.
おるんな？どこおったん？
Are you here? Where were you?
どこだ！？
Where is it!?
おい！あ、お前…
Hey! Ah, you...
待て、そいつがルパンだ！おら！
Wait, that guy's Lupin! Take this!
季節50年、ようやくここまでやつを追いかけてきたが、いったいどこにいるのか？
Fifty years... we've finally chased him this far, but where on earth is he?
何もわからない。
I have no idea.
一体あいつはどこにいるんだ？
Where on earth is that guy?!
なんの？気のせいか。
What? Just my imagination?
どこに行ったんだ？
Where did he go?
いや、いるじゃねえか、どう考えたってどこだよ！
No, he's right here! No matter how you think about it, where is he?!
おい、姿を現せ！
Hey, show yourself!
さあおいで！おいで、おいで！
Now come on! Come here, come here!
そう、いいこで、いいこで、いいこだ。よしよし。
That's right, good boy, good boy, good boy. There, there.
なんてだ！何になんだ！
What is this! What is this?!
くそっ、えっ？待って。
Damn it, huh? Wait.
おれを…あっ、あっ、あっ。
Me... ah, ah, ah.
次こそは…
Next time...
Happy Birthday to you, Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday dear Polka! Happy Birthday to you!
これはBGMだったかもしれない…！
This might have been BGM...!
というわけで、歌いたてました！ポルカおるよー！
And so, I sang it! Polka's here!
ほらライブの動きの、おまるポルカですー！
Look, it's Omaru Polka with live movements!
ついに、ついに、ついに今日誕生日を迎えました！ハッピーバースデーのコメントありがとう！
Finally, finally, finally today I welcomed my birthday! Thanks for the Happy Birthday comments!
帰ってる、帰ってる！サンキュー、ハッピーバースデー！
Going back, going back! Thank you, Happy Birthday!
いや、緊張して絡まってるのはいつものこと…ええ？までもあるいはまあ、ちょっと
Well, being nervous and tongue-tied is business as usual... eh? Or rather, well, a little...
なんやろな。ちょ、うーん、今日もここからお届けしてるんだが
What could it be? Well, um, today I'm broadcasting from here too, but
今みたいにちょっともう一回歌おうか、じゃあ。歌をみんなと一緒にもう一回歌おうか、じゃあ。
Like right now, let's sing it one more time, shall we? Let's sing the song together with everyone one more time.
歌おう歌おう、行くよ！せーの！Happy Birthday to you...
Let's sing, let's sing, here we go! Ready, set! Happy Birthday to you...
Happy Birthday to you...
Happy Birth Day to me...
Happy Birthday to me...
Dear Polka!
Happy Birth Day... Dear Polka!
Happy Birthday... Dear Polka!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
エール届いてます
I'm receiving your cheers.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
超幸せなんだが
I'm so happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃめっちゃ言われて、お、サンキュー、サンキュー！
Everyone's saying it so much. Oh, thank you, thank you!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
まあでもね、なんだろう、うーん、まあ、ざいんもおるし、コメントもあるねんけど
Well, but, I wonder... um, well, Za'in is here too, and there are comments...
まあちょっと悲しいような、まあ曲もこんな盛り上がって照明もあるんやけど
Well, it's kind of sad, even though the song is so upbeat and there's lighting...
まあでもコメントあるから寂しくないか。いっか、こんな感じでじゃあ
Well, but I have comments so I'm not lonely. Oh well, let's go with this.
じゃあこんな感じで今日はやっていきたい
So let's go ahead and do it like this today—
お？
Huh?
なにこれ？
What is this?
え？ケーキ？あるんか？
Eh? Cake? There is one?
ケーキあるらしい。え？
There's apparently cake. Eh?
ないないないないない！
No, no, no, no, no!
おお、チャレンジ！
Oh, a challenge!
なにそれ！？
What is that!?
おい、おい、座長が、お前ポルカだぞ！なんでこんなチャレンジに成功しないと食べられませんって言ってくるんだ、おかしいだろ！
Hey, hey, the manager—you're Polka! Why are you telling me I can't eat it unless I succeed at a challenge? That's weird!
え？どんなチャレンジ？
Eh? What kind of challenge?
え、もぐつな渡りしたし、えっと
Eh, I did the tightrope walk, and um—
え、つな渡りしたじゃん、んで、玉乗りもしたじゃん、ジャグリング、あ、コロナ、恒例のチャレンジなんかどんなんだろう？
Eh, I did the tightrope walk, and then I did the ball riding, juggling... ah, the customary challenges up until now—what are they like?
え、なんか先輩方がやってるようなチャレンジなのかな？
Eh, is it like a challenge that the seniors have done?
え、どんなんだろう？今までどんなチャレンジやってきた？
Eh, what could it be? What kind of challenges have I done up until now?
まさかそれは無いでしょう。ビビりするかな？
Surely it wouldn't be that. Would I be scared?
電流？いや電流はまだ、お、終わっ
Electricity? No, electricity is still—oh, wait—
うわ、まっじかよ！
Whoa, seriously?!
いや、ガチなやつ
No, this is for real!
いや、これよ、だってもう、やばい奴だよ！
No, look at this, I mean this is dangerous!
これ、いいの？これ、燃
Is this okay? This is burn—
あ,なんかもう火の輪くぐりって、こう,なんか可愛い,本能的なエフェクトかと思った,ちがうちがう
Ah, I thought "fire ring jump" was just some cute, instinctive effect, but no, no!
耳いった気がする。熱っ、熱っ、熱っ、熱っ、マジで熱っ
I feel like my ears got hit. Hot, hot, hot, hot, seriously hot!
え、これ、ししろんがやるやつじゃん。なんでポルカやるの？
Eh, isn't this what Botan does? Why is Polka doing it?
おかしいだろ！そもそも、しし朗に、なんで座長がやるんだこれ、おいおいおい、おかしいぞ、ぶんぶんぶんぶん
That's weird! In the first place, why is the manager doing Shishiro's thing? Hey hey hey, that's weird, buzz buzz buzz...
え、じゃあ、なんか、頑張るんで、が、頑張れ！の声ください！が、頑張れ！の声ください！
Eh, well, like, I'll do my best, so please give me your "Do your best!" voices! Please give me your "Do your best!" voices!
捕食する側から捕食される側になる。いや燃えるとか、これまずいだって、明日から配信なくなるかもしれないワンチャン
Going from the predator to the prey. No, if I burn, this is bad, because my streams might stop starting tomorrow, one chance.
え、お、お願いします！誕生日のひとです！頑張ってって言ってください！ありがとうございます！それでは、きっと、ざいんくん、ドラムロールを、あんのかな？わからん、言ってみた今。
Eh, o-please! It's the birthday person! Please tell me to do my best! Thank you very much! Well then, surely, Za'in-kun, the drum roll—is there one? I don't know, I just said that.
あ、あるんだ！あるんだ！いつ行くんだこれ？
Ah, there is one! There is one! When am I going?
行くぞ！わっだ！
Here I go! Whoa!
え、どう？え？今、行けた？え？燃えた？足燃え、え？
Eh, how was it? Eh? Did I make it just now? Eh? Did I burn? My foot burned, eh?
燃えてるの燃えてるの、へいへい
It's burning, it's burning, hey hey.
あ、意外ともしかしたらこれ、熱くないんじゃない？熱っ、熱っ、熱っ
Ah, maybe this actually isn't hot? Hot, hot, hot!
はい、えー、あっち、あっちな。はい。
Yes, um, ouch, it's hot. Yes.
ということでね、え、見事成功しました！ありがとうございます！
And with that, um, I successfully completed it! Thank you very much!
あー、ケーキ見てください！このコメントの温度感とこの、あの「ケーキあります」って言ってくれる優しいざいんとね、コメントのざいん。
Ah, look at the cake! Look at the temperature of these comments, and kind Za'in telling me "There is cake," and Za'in in the comments.
見てこの男が、全然怪しい怪しいってすげえ言われてんだけど、おかしいだろ！
Look at this guy, everyone's saying how super suspicious he is, that's weird!
あの、あ、やったケーキだ！嬉しい、ありがとう！
Um, ah, yay, it's cake! I'm so happy, thank you!
どこだろう？
Where could it be?
どっかからのケーキ？
A cake from somewhere?
めっちゃ重いやん！
It's super heavy!
曲でかいね。
The music is so loud.
え、いいの？
Eh, is it okay?
ケーキじゃん！
It's a cake!
ケーキだよ、これ。
It's a cake, this is.
初めて見たかもしれない。
I might be seeing one for the first time.
ケーキ、ケーキ。
Cake, cake.
え、待って、マジでこれある。みんな驚くかもしれないけど、ここに、あのガチでケーキが用意されてる。
Wait, this is seriously here. You guys might be surprised, but an actual cake has been prepared right here.
食べていいの？
Is it okay to eat?
今、え？だって配信中だよ？
Wait, what? I'm in the middle of a stream right now!
配信中だよって言いながらフォークをテニスにしてしまった。
While saying I was streaming, I ended up treating the fork like a tennis racket.
いいんだ？
Is it okay?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、早速いただきます。
Well then, let's dig right in.
え？え？幸せ！
Huh? Huh? So happy!
うん、フォーク美味しい。
Mmm, the fork is delicious.
フォークのお味は？
How does the fork taste?
無限！
Infinite!
んめえ！甘いもんうま！おら！
So good! Sweets are amazing! Take that!
最高に夢だな。
This is the ultimate dream.
もっと食いてえ。
I want to eat more.
食い足りねえよ。
I'm not full yet.
あ、食い足りねえよ。
Ah, I'm not full yet.
もうなくなったのか？
Is it already gone?
おら！
Take that!
ほら、イチゴ乗っけた部分が、う、うまい！
Look, the part with the strawberry is s-so good!
おら！おっ！えい！
Take that! Oop! Hiyah!
あ、無茶！おらーい！
Ah, wild! Hurrah!
これすごくない、なんかけ？
Isn't this amazing, somehow?
このまま
Just like this
あ、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、
Ah, ma-ma-ma-ma-ma-ma...
ペロリ！食べました！
Devoured! I ate it!
あとはポルカが美味しくいただきます！このね、
Afterwards, Polka will deliciously eat it! This, um,
あ、待ってこれ、ケーキ投げちゃったらイチゴちゃんじゃん。やばっ！
Ah, wait, if I throw the cake, it's Strawberry-chan. Oh no!
このね、あのプレートはね、あとで大事に取っとくから。
This plate, um, I'll keep it safely later.
やったー！超美味しかった。
Yay! It was super delicious.
美味しすぎる。
Too delicious.
あーもう、食べさせられなくなっちゃった。
Ah man, I can't be fed anymore.
フォーク
Fork
食べられなくなっちゃった。
I can't eat anymore.
もうちょっと食べたかったな。
I wish I could have eaten a bit more.
まあいっか。
Oh well.
今日はケーキじゃないよね？
Today is not cake, right?
ケーキじゃないよね？
メインははもちろん、
The main event is of course
ライブソウル！歌う！シングソング！
Live soul! Singing! Sing song!
ということで、何曲か歌ってもらおうと思います。
So, I'm going to have you sing a few songs.
ちょっと待っててね！バイバイ！イエーイ！
Wait a moment! Bye-bye! Yay!
ケーキ
Cake
あー
Ah...
あーもう何も考えたくない
Ah, I don't want to think about anything anymore.
ていうか、もう寝よ
Or rather, I'll just sleep.
ケーキ
Cake
今日はケーキの夢が見られる
Today I can dream of cake.
うん、むにゃむにゃ
Yeah, mumble mumble
ちょっと食えたな、これ
I got to eat a bit of this.
ああ、このままケーキになるんだろうな
Ah, I guess I'll just become a cake.
ケーキになっていくんだ、みんな人間は
Becoming a cake, all humans are.
ああ、このまま悠々になりてえ、悠々になりてえな
Ah, I want to become leisurely like this...
悠々になっていくんだ
I'm becoming leisurely...
くちづけキポンヌ...
Kuchizuke Kiponnu...
時はブランニュー アキハバラ
Time is brand new Akihabara
黄昏にそまる
Dyeing in the twilight
寄り添った私たち
We snuggled close together
かげぼうし二つ
Two silhouettes
もしも地球最後の日は
If the Earth's final day were to come,
打ち上げ花火みたいがいいな
it'd be nice if it looked like fireworks.
幼く笑う横顔を半分照らして
It half-illuminates your smiling profile,
街で流れるバースデイソング
a birthday song playing in the streets,
吹き消した芯の灯火
and the blown-out wick's light.
願う小さな希望が叶うように
So that small wishes can come true,
うれしいときも悲しいないものね
sometimes it's happy, sometimes it's sad.
光って飛び散って壊れていく
Shining, scattering, and breaking apart,
地球が滅亡する素敵な夜のこと
it's a wonderful night when the Earth meets its end.
小さな街で2人は永遠に変わるものね
In a small town, the two of us will change forever.
今だって手形が触れ合ったのは偶然と君はまさかと思ってたの
Let's continue that night—1999.
永遠の時間切れの恋を繰り返してばかりだけど今日の君はどこか違う
永遠の時間切れの恋を高速超えて抜けたら君にこういうの口づけ希望ぬ
Let's continue that night—1999.
草の隙間に学校や友達全てがずっと続くって誰もが考えてた
Drinking down the melon soda,
永遠にオンオフレはなくこの世の夢は儚く石を剥なわえぬかが音を漏れないように君が帰るべきは未来なんかじゃなく
only the cherry blossom petals remain.
現在過去フューチャそう今この瞬間ほら光が点滅して二人を包んで秋の夕暮れ暮れに二人は二人は二人は
Our vivid days, having known the end,
永遠の時間切れの恋を繰り返してばかりだけど今日の君はどこか違う
turning everything inside out.
永遠の時間切れの恋を高速超えて抜けたら君にこういうの口づけ希望ぬ
Shining, scattering, and breaking apart,
surely soon that night will arrive,
口づけ希望ぬ
when everyone holds the hand of someone they love.
付き合ってよって言われなくても伝わっているとまさかと思ってたの
Tell me the end of that night—1999.
永遠の時間切れの恋を繰り返してばかりだけど今日の君はどこか違う
World-class villains,
永遠の時間切れの恋を高速超えて抜けたら君にこういうの口づけ希望ぬ
and those kind children who tend to dream,
永遠の時間切れの恋を繰り返してばかりだけど今日の君はどこか違う
will both equally surrender their bodies in the end.
永遠の時間切れの恋を高速超えて抜けたら君にこういうの口づけ希望ぬ
Even the things we couldn't say,
口づけ希望ぬ
saying goodbye and sorry for back then,
永久のえんはなくこの世の夢は儚く口を離はなえぬかのどがおぼろげなように君が帰るべきは未来なんかじゃなく
we'll hold each other tight and become stars, I suppose.
永遠の時間切れの恋を高速超えて抜けたら君にこういうの口づけ希望ぬ
Shining, scattering, and breaking apart,
昼間の流れ星 電車で追いかけて
A passing star pursued by the train,
見慣れた改札で つかまえたの
caught by a familiar ticket gate.
風変わりな部屋に住み それとなく疲れてて
Living in an unusual room,
とはいえ お仕事は とても順調なの
even so, work is going quite smoothly.
通り雨を 振り返ったら
Looking back at the passing shower,
路地裏から 猫が見てたの
a cat was watching from the alley.
この声 聞こえていますか?
Can you hear this voice?
私 って ちょっと強くなった と 思う よ
I think I've gotten a little stronger,
だけど きっと
but I'm sure...
明日 地球 が ごなごな になって
Even if tomorrow the Earth shatters into pieces
宇宙 の ちり になって 消えたら
and vanishes into cosmic dust,
プリズム みたいな おしゃれ し て
I'll dress up like a prism
最低 ！ って そう 言って 寝込んで やる
and go to sleep saying "How awful!"
強がり ばかり くたくた になって
I'm always putting on a brave face,
泣い ちゃう こと も ある から さ
and sometimes I might even cry,
ぎゅっと 抱き 寄せ て
so hold me tight.
それだけ なの それだけ なの お願い
That's all I ask, that's all I want.
夜しじまに溶けてくかいでんぱを
Dissolving into the silence of the night,
手探りで描き留めたあの日は
the day I sketched out by feel
まだ朝も明けていないのに
even though dawn hadn't broken yet,
終わりばかりを気にしていた
I was already worrying about the end.
この声聞こえていますか?
Can you hear this voice?
私って結構頑張ってると思うよ
I think I'm working pretty hard,
だけどきっと
but I'm sure...
明日地球がごなごなになって
Even if tomorrow the Earth shatters into pieces
宇宙のちりになって消えたら
and vanishes into cosmic dust,
オーロラみたいなメイクして
I'll put on aurora-like makeup
最低!ってそう言って死んでやる
and die saying "How awful!"
怖くはないよ ぐだぐだになって
I'm not scared, even if I get clumsy
怠けることもあるけどさ
and sometimes might even slack off,
ぎゅっと抱き寄せて
so hold me tight.
無理してるの?
Are you pushing yourself too hard?
無理してるよ ごめんね
I am pushing myself, I'm sorry.
瞬いている ツムグスカ
Twinkling Tsumugusaka,
さらさら流れる 星の行方はいずこへ
where do the gently flowing stars go?
「ここへおいでて
"Come here,
君がいるなら
if you are here,
たとえ世界が終わる日も
even on a day the world ends,
理不尽も矛盾も抱きしめて
embracing both unreason and contradiction,
最高のステージ見せてやる
I'll show you the greatest stage!
360° あおぞら に 浮かんで
Floating in the 360-degree blue sky,
たゆたって 宇宙船 つかまえ に いこう
let's go catch the drifting spaceship.
きっと約束だよ
It's definitely a promise,
約束だよ お願い」
it's a promise, I beg you."
お願い
I beg you,
I beg you.
君がいるなら
If you're here,
たとえ世界が終わる日も
even if it's the day the world ends,
涙も笑いも夢も抱きしめて
holding tears, smiles, and dreams close,
最高のステージ見せてやる
I'll show you the ultimate stage!
360度空に浮かんで
Floating in the 360-degree sky,
流れてた流星手綱に捕まえに行こう
let's go catch the shooting stars and jump.
きっと約束だよ
It's definitely a promise,
約束だよ お願い
it's a promise, I beg you.
お願い
I beg you,
I beg you.
あす地球がこなごなになってもでした。
Even if the earth were to shatter tomorrow...
あ、あ、拍手ありがとうございます。
Ah, ah, thank you for the applause.
えっと、そうですね、まあ、残りの2曲も...
Um, let's see, well, the remaining two songs also...
あ、言っちゃった！ あの、残り2曲頼んだんだけど、
Ah, I said it! Um, I requested two more songs,
2曲ともすごいぶち上がる感じじゃないけど、
but neither of them is super hype, but...
まあ、今日ならではっていうかさ、歌うので、おお願いいたします。
well, since it's today, I'll be singing it, so please look forward to it.
そちらも、よろしくお願いします。聞いてください。「花に亡霊」
That one too, please look forward to it. Please listen to "Ghost in a Flower".
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座ったまま、アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
Sitting in the summer shade, tossing ice cream into my mouth, waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
世の中の全部嘘ばらけ
Wondering if all of the world's lies...
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
We laughed about going to find true value together.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that things remaining in shape aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming,
僕は描いている
And I am painting...
眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
What I see in my eyes is a summer ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
Forgetting even memories,
浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭いて夏めく
Taking shallow breaths, wiping sweat as summer approaches.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座った頃
Back when we sat in the summer shade,
遠くの丘から顔を出した雲があったじゃないか
Wasn't there a cloud peeking out from a distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして、馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
You tried to grab it, cutting through the sky like a fool,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて笑って握って見せて
While I drew a single cloud on paper, smiling and showing it to you.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because things remaining in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔も失くして
Losing even our faces for now,
言葉も全部忘れて
Forgetting all words too,
君は笑ってる、夏を待ってる僕ら亡霊だ
You're smiling—we're ghosts waiting for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Teach me more of your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
Teach me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because things that resonate in the heart aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
さよならだって教えて
Tell me even how to say goodbye,
今も見るんだよ、夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
I still see it now—a ghost in the flowers blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Time, not words,
時間じゃなくて心を
Heart, not time,
浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭いて夏めく
Taking shallow breaths, wiping sweat as summer approaches.
夏の匂いがする
I can smell the scent of summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座ったまま、アイスを口に放り込んで風を
Sitting in the summer shade, tossing ice cream into my mouth, the wind...
最後の曲です。
This is the final song.
街明かり照らした
Illuminated by streetlights,
賑やかな笑い声と
with lively laughter
路地裏の足跡
and footsteps in the back alleys.
伝えたい想いは
How far did the feelings I wanted to convey
どれだけ届いたんだろう
manage to reach, I wonder?
いつも振り返って確かめる
I always look back to make sure.
いつでも迷わず
Without ever hesitating,
キミはきっとどんな
you will surely come after
ボクも追いかけてくれるから
whoever I am.
じっと見つめた
I gazed intently
キミの瞳に映った
at the signs of my life reflected in your eyes,
ボクが生きたシルシ
the proof that I lived.
何度も途切れそうな鼓動
A heartbeat that seemed to falter time and again,
強く強く鳴らした
beating stronger and stronger.
今日を越えてみたいんだ
I want to try and get through today.
手にした幸せを
Fearing that I might lose
失うことを恐れて
the happiness I've found,
立ち止まっているより
rather than standing still,
一つ一つ大きな
I'll try to make as many big
出来るだけ多くの
smiles bloom as I possibly can.
笑顔咲かせようとたくらむ
Plotting to make them bloom.
思い出すボクらの
Remembering the days
通り過ぎた日々が
that we passed through,
いつも輝いて見える様に
they always seem to shine.
ぎゅっと握った
Holding tightly onto
キミの温もりで感じた
your warmth, I felt
ボクら繋いだ証
the proof that we were connected.
キミと今同じ
Walking towards the future
あの日描いた未来を歩いている
we drew that day at the same speed as you.
いくつ願い叶えても
Even if all my prayers were granted,
キミと過ごしたい新しい明日をすぐに
I want a new tomorrow to spend with you right away.
次々にボクはきっとまた願ってしまうから
Because I'll end up praying for more again and again.
流れてく時間は容赦無く
Because flowing time shows no mercy,
いつかボクらをさらうから
sweeping us away someday,
瞬きした瞬間の隙に
in the blink of an eye,
キミの見せる全てを見落とさないように
so I don't miss anything you show me.
じっと見つめた
I gazed intently
キミの瞳に映った
at the signs of my life reflected in your eyes,
ボクが生きたシルシ
the proof that I lived.
何度も途切れそうな鼓動
A heartbeat that seemed to falter time and again,
強く強く鳴らした
beating stronger and stronger.
今日を越えていけなくても
Even if you can't make it through today,
キミと生きた今日をボクは忘れない
I won't forget the day I lived with you.
僕は忘れない
I won't forget...
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
跳ね返るわけないか
There's no way it would bounce back, huh?
空気は気持ちいいな
The air feels nice.
あそこに求む先輩いるじゃん
There's a help-wanted senpai over there.
おーい！求む先輩！
Hey! Help-wanted senpai!
誰か 誰か
Someone... Someone...
これ大丈夫か？
Is this okay?
まあどうにかなるだろ
Well, it'll somehow work out.
明日からも息が続きそうだ
Looks like I can keep breathing tomorrow too.
あ！UFO！
Ah! A UFO!
嘘だよ
Just kidding.
あのさ、白詰草冠にしてさ
You know, making a white clover crown...
どこにかぶろうかこれ
Where am I supposed to wear this?
うーん、かぶれないや
Hmm, can't wear it.
じゃあ…はい！あげる！
Well then... Here! I'll give it to you!
いやー
Man...
お見事、お見事
Brilliant, absolutely brilliant.
もうね、すっかりアイドルだなこれで
Man, I'm totally an idol now with this.
数百年ぶりのアイドルっぽいことした！
I did something idol-like for the first time in hundreds of years!
あ、反省会はあとですけどね、反省会はあとですけどさ
Ah, the reflection meeting is later though, but...
ちゃんと反省します
I'll reflect properly.
というわけで、えー最後に歌ったのは『花の匂い』と『白詰草』！
So, um, the songs I sang at the end were 'Hana no Nioi' and 'Shirotsumekusa'!
いりちらさないようにめっちゃカウント作ってもらったのに…
Even though I had them make a super good count so I wouldn't scatter things...
いや、反省会はあとでするんだった！
No, wait, I was supposed to have the reflection meeting later!
まあ…やべえな、ちょっと
Well... this is bad, man.
まあまだ早かったんだな。でも結構、あのもうアイドルじゃない、アイドル、めっちゃいいこと言ってる！
Well, it was still too early. But quite, um, I'm already an idol, an idol, I'm saying such good things!
やったやった！え、清純派ですか？
Yay yay! Wh-are you going for pure idol?
清純？清純？清純な感じする？
Pure? Pure? Do I look pure?
どうですか、どうですか？
What do you think, what do you think?
もう完全に清純？
Completely pure?
立ち振る舞い。どうですか？最強のアイドル？
Demeanor. How is it? The strongest idol?
え、最強のアイドル？
Eh, the strongest idol?
うそ？あ、やった！やった！うれし！やった！ポルカはアイドルだよ！イエーイ！うれし！ヤッホー！
Really? Ah, yay! Yay! I'm so happy! Yay! Polka is an idol! Yay! I'm so happy! Woohoo!
どきどきどきどき。いや、いいね。じゃあこの感じでさ、この配信どうしていこうかな、この後は。えーと
Thumping, thumping. Man, nice. Well then, with this vibe, how should I proceed with this stream from here on? Um...
あれ？
Huh?
おまる…あ、ポルカ！
Omaru... Ah, Polka!
清純ポルカ！清純のポルカです。えへへ
Pure Polka! I'm Pure Polka. Ehehe.
ポルカ！あ、はい！はい、ポルカと申します。
Polka! Ah, yes! Yes, my name is Polka.
えっと、ご起生、ホラライブ、ご起生、おまるポルカです。よろしくお願いします。
Um, 5th generation, Hololive 5th generation, Omaru Polka. Nice to meet you.
あ、ごめんなさい、間違えました。
Ah, sorry, I made a mistake.
すみません！ポルカ、失礼します。失礼します。失礼します。
Sorry! Polka, excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
えっと、来てくださったのはご起生の皆さんのです。
Um, those who came are everyone from the 5th generation.
え！可愛かったでしょー！可愛かったでしょー！
Eh! Wasn't it cute?! Wasn't it cute?!
えもかった？あ、えもかったわ。なんか、お前消えるのかみたいな感じがするけど
Was it emotional? Ah, it was emotional. Like, it feels like 'Are you disappearing, you?'
え？消えろは？消えたらどうすんだよ？どうすんだよ？
Eh? Disappear? What am I supposed to do if I disappear? What do I do?
びっくりした！ありがとう今日来てくれて！
Whoa, you scared me! Thanks for coming today!
いぇい、いぇい。
Yay, yay.
でさ、どうかな、可愛いだけでポルカ今後生きていけるかな？
I wonder if Polka can survive going forward
on cuteness alone?
うーん、なんかもうもう一つ武器が欲しいね。
Hmm, I feel like I need one more weapon.
ああ、そうだね。プロデューサーさん、プロデューサーさん！
Ah, that's right. Producer-san, Producer-san!
ポルカ頑張ります。どういう、ポルカPとしてね。
Polka will do her best. As a Polka P...
ちょっとね、面白さもちょっと欲しいよな。
I want a bit of humor too.
面白さ？今、あの、作った台本を読んでいただいておりますので、あの、全然、あの、この子たちはポルカが勝手にやってるわけではないんです。
Humor? We're having you read the script we made,
so it's not like these kids are doing it on their own...
本当に。
Seriously.
台本？ないから、そんなのないから！
There's no such thing, there's no script like that!
はい。面白さですか？
Right. Humor, you say?
面白さ。
Humor.
そうね、面白さ、台本読んでね、ポルカ歌うよ。
That's right, humor. Read the script,
and Polka will sing.
ええと、読むな！台本読むな、読むな！
Um, don't read it! Don't read the script!
ええと、面白いていうのは一体どういうことなんですか？
Um, what does "funny" actually mean?
じゃあ、今日はね、そんなね、おまるポルカさんにに対して
So today, regarding such Omaru Polka-san,
我々ね、ま、ご期生の3人がね、なんか、アイテムを1つずつ使っていって、ちょっとおまるポルカさんに面白いことをしてもらおうかなと思ってます。
we, the three Gen 5 members, will use items
one by one to make Omaru Polka do something funny.
え、え、え？
Eh, eh, eh?
びっくり、物ボケみたいな感じね。そうそうそう。物ボケえ！
Surprise—sort of like prop comedy.
- That's right. - Prop comedy?!
もうちょい新鮮な反応してくれ！分かった？嘘、物ボケって何？
Give a fresher reaction! Understood?
- No way, what's prop comedy?
それどうやってやるの？どういうこと？でも私が紹介するんだって。
How do you do that? What do you mean?
- But I'm introducing it.
これから使用できる、あのね、あの、物ボケするんだったら、ポルカこれ使えると思う。あの、ちょっと待って、物ボケアイテム持ってくるわ。
If you're doing prop comedy, I think Polka can use this.
Hold on, I'll bring a prop comedy item.
あ、持ってくる？持んできて？頼むわ。
Ah, bringing it? Bring it? Please.
え、わかんない。ここら辺の、ちょっと早く持ってきて。ええと、これとか？
Eh, I don't know. Around here—
bring it quickly. Um, how about this?
どれ？あの、お、見せてごらん。ハン、ハンマー。ピコハン。
Which one? Show me. A hammer.
A squeaky hammer.
ああ、いいじゃん、いいじゃん！ピコハン、ピコハン。
Ah, nice, nice! A squeaky hammer!
おう、ここには？これね、お肉。うわ、むしゃむしゃむしゃ、むしゃむしゃむしゃ、他には？
And here? This, meat. Nom, nom, nom...
What else?
はい、他のですね。まだある。ええと、ええと。
Yes, others. There's still more. Um...
あの、これ、あの、獅子のさ、あ、手裏剣だ。
Um, this, um, Shishi's... ah, a shuriken.
おれ、おれ、おれ、うれい。うれい。お、いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
Me, me, me, Urei! Urei!
- Oh, nice, nice.
危ないぞ。危ないぞ。もしかしてまだある？まだある？あ、もしかしてまだあるよ。えっと。
It's dangerous. Could there still be more?
Ah, maybe there is. Um...
こちらです。こちら、こちら。
Here it is. Here, here.
ラミィちゃんのおでんじゃない？あ、おでんだ！
Isn't this Lamy-chan's oden? Ah, it's oden!
おでんが落ちちゃった！おでん落ちちゃったけど大丈夫かな？こんな感じで、おでんもありますよ。
The oden fell! But will it be okay?
Like this, we also have oden.
はい。おでん美味しそう。
Yes. Oden looks delicious.
いいな。おでんいいな。
Nice. Oden is nice.
え、まだあるの？
Eh, is there still more?
あれ、なんでよ。
Huh, why though.
光るんですよ、これ。すぐ出てくるじゃん。
It glows, you see. It comes right out.
再利用は大事ですよ、やっぱり。
Reuse is important, after all.
や号、や号、や号、再利用していこう。
Yagoo, Yagoo, let's reuse.
美味し、お前自分のところの写真を再利用してくるんだけどさ、
Delicious—you're reusing your own photo!
いいよ、おまるより大きくしてあっていいよ。
It's fine, it's bigger than Omaru so it's fine.
おまるじゃないじゃん。そうだよ。
That's not Omaru. - That's right.
じゃあ、おまるを見せてよ。
Then show Omaru.
これがありますけど。
We have this, though.
ラインナップがすげえな。奇跡的に並んじゃったんだけど。
The lineup is amazing.
They miraculously lined up.
本当だ、奇跡的に並んでんじゃん、私達。
Really, we've miraculously lined up.
やめて、やめて！おい、やめろって！ご期生のメンバーじゃないから！
Stop it, stop it! Hey, stop that!
We're not Gen 5 members!
もっと届けといてもっと。
Send it more, more.
寄せんな、寄せんな！どうでした？どうでした？こんな感じ。
Don't bring it closer!
- How was it? How was it? Like this.
ご期生になっちゃった。
It became Gen 5.
お父さんみたい。
Like a father.
本当だよ！授業参観に来たお父さんみたいになってんじゃんかよ。
It's like a dad who came to open class!
やだな、ちょっとやめよう。
Gross, let's stop this.
ごめん、じゃあね、これを使って。
Sorry, then, using this...
おまるんがすごい大爆笑の渦に巻き込むような面白いことをしてくれると。
Omarun will do something funny that drags everyone
into a vortex of roaring laughter.
はい！何を使いたいか、教えてもろて。
Yes! Tell us what you want to use.
ポルカ頑張ります、どれ行く？誰から行く？誰が早く？
Polka will do her best. Which one? Who goes first?
じゃあネネの行くは、ネネ。
Then Nene's turn, Nene.
あ、オッケー。いい？
Ah, okay. Is that good?
うん、じゃあ、じゃあ、お肉を使って、
Yeah, then, using the meat...
ぐずぐずな、ぐずぐずな。
Messily, messily.
面白かった、最初見てやんだ。
It was funny, watch from the start.
はい、お肉を使って、ネネのことを褒めてください。
Yes, using the meat, please praise Nene.
なおかつね、みんなを笑顔にさせてね。よろしく。
And make everyone smile, too. Please.
もう面白いんだろな、大爆笑だわ。
It's probably already funny, total roaring laughter.
わかりました。
Understood.
いや、楽しみだな。分かりました。
Man, I'm looking forward to it. Understood.
じゃあ、行きます！はい。
Then, here we go! Yes.
もうね、ネネはこの、
Already, Nene is this...
焼けた肉とは違う。ネネは違う、うん。
Unlike cooked meat. Nene is different, yeah.
ミディアムレアなんだ。もう、美味しさがね。
Medium rare. The deliciousness...
これからどんどん、生焼け、詰まって、つまって、美味しくなっていく。
From now on more and more, undercooked, stuffed...
Stuffed, getting more delicious.
もうこれは、もう、違う、だめ。
This is already... no, wait.
あの、これは
Um, this is...
全然詰まんない。
Completely not funny.
焼けている。つまり、これから食べられるだけ。でもネネはミディアムレアだから、これからさらに焼きたい人は焼けばいいし、
It's cooked. Meaning, it can just be eaten.
But Nene is medium rare, so those who want to grill it further can...
んが
Ngah,
別に望んで焼かれてもいい
it's fine if I'm roasted by choice.
炎上？
Cancelled?
それでも焼かれてもいいよ
Even if I get roasted, that's fine.
いや炎上さ、調理されてもいい
Well, cancelled... being cooked is fine.
あの、調理されてもいい
Um, being cooked is fine too.
ネネがこれから自分で磨き上げて美味しくなっていくもいい
It's also fine if Nene polishes herself up and gets tastier from now on!
なるほど
I see.
お前ら食べてくれんの？じゃあもし焼いたらネネが、私はミディアムレアが好きなんだね。
Will you guys eat it? So if you grill it, Nene... I like medium rare, you know.
うえっ、今食べてもいいか
Ugh, can I eat it right now?
今いいよ、食べて
Yeah, go ahead, eat it.
いいんだって！
I said it's fine!
明日、明日ハイパーネネチなのにいいの今食べて
Tomorrow—tomorrow is Hyper Nenechi, is it really fine to eat her now?!
いいよ、食べちゃって
It's fine, just eat her.
え？え？え？食べるのかよ！
Eh? Eh? Eh? You're actually gonna eat her?!
じゃあ、このあとポルカが美味しくいただきました
Well then, afterwards, Polka enjoyed eating her deliciously.
はい、というわけで生焼けのネネでした
Yup, so that was undercooked Nene.
ねぇ、ミディアムレアのこと生焼けって言うのやめてくれる？ちょっとミディアムレアなんだけど、おこるよ。
Hey, will you stop calling medium rare "undercooked"? It's medium rare, you know, I'm getting mad.
ネネミディアムレアだね。おこるよ。なんでそういうこと言うの？
Nene is medium rare, see. I'm getting mad. Why would you say something like that?
なんならレアとか美味しいじゃん、ね、ししろん。
Rare is even delicious, right, Shishiron?
はぁー、なかなかこれはちょっとおーまるには厳しかったようなので、輪投げを持ってきたいと思います。
Haa... this seems a bit too harsh for Omaru, so I'd like to bring out the ring toss.
お願いしますよ
Please do.
これねちょっとね、あまりにも具体的すぎて、逆にできなかったパターンかもしれないから
This might have been too specific, leading to a pattern where it couldn't be done.
あのさっき日輪があったじゃん。もうあれを使ってもボケてくださいて、こうシンプルだね。
Um, earlier there was a circle of fire. You could use that and "please be funny"—that's simple, right?
シンプルじゃん、それは。
That's simple.
そう、それを... これを使ってくぐるって、そうそうそうそれよ。分かった、えっと... まあ分かったよ。
Yes, that... crawling through this using that, yes, exactly that. I got it, um... Well, I got it.
ちょっと待って、今、今... あ、降りてきてる。
Hold on, right now... Ah, it's coming down.
わくわく！あ、煽ってきてる。煽る煽る煽ってきてる。あ、降りてきてる降りてきてる。お、いいね。わくわく！
Exciting! Ah, it's provoking me. Provoking, provoking, provoking. Ah, it's coming down, coming down. Oh, nice. Exciting!
ちょ、ネネ、いつものさ... デデデデ、くれない？
Hey Nene, won't you give me your usual... de-de-de-de?
デデデデデデデ！あ、まだ早ぇっすね、ねねさん。あ、だめ。今こういう感じになってから、今たぶん来るって言ってくれるんで、今いいですか？ちょっとカーンって言ったあとで、はい！いきます！
Dededededede! Ah, it's still too early, Nene-san. Ah, no. Now that it's gotten like this, she'll probably say "now", so is it good now? After it goes "clang", yes! Here we go!
デデデデデデーーー！通り抜け...
Dededede—! Passing through...
くぐり！これを使ってくぐると... うわあーーーー！ここは...
crawling through! Crawling through using this... Uwaaaah! This place is...
北極？ポルカ北極に来ちゃった。
The Arctic? Polka has come to the Arctic.
どうしよう？えっ、すごい寒い、無理や。あ、もう無理だ帰ろう！帰ろう帰ろう帰ろう！
What should I do? Eh, super cold, no way. Ah, no way, let's go home! Let's go home, go home, go home!
よいしょ！あ、みんな！ただいまー！
Heave-ho! Ah, everyone! I'm home!
ポルカ大変です。お帰りなさい。大変です。冷え冷えです。
Polka, it's terrible. Welcome back. It's terrible. It's freezing cold.
コメント欄が北極です。コメント欄が。
The comment section is the Arctic. The comment section is.
あ、自らちょっと寒いの作っちゃったから。
Ah, because I made it cold myself.
自ら墓穴掘ったの？逆にそこまでニコしたネタだったってことか。なるほどな、なるほど。
You dug your own grave? So it was a joke you pushed that far, huh. I see, I see.
じゃあ、それはすごい。ロミィだったらどうすんだよ。
Well, that's amazing. What would Romy do?
まさか、人に振らないと... これ使ってどうするんだよ。
No way, if you don't throw it at someone... What are you supposed to do with this?
次が、次が、次が...
Next is, next is, next is...
次、次、次、次、次、はい！いけいけ！はい！
Next, next, next, next, next, yes! Go go! Yes!
はい、どうしますか？次行くか。じゃあ、私で行きましょう。
Yes, what should we do? Go next? Well, let's go with me.
はい。はい。じゃあどうしようかな？え、もうYAGOOはいいかな？
Yes. Yes. So what should I do? Eh, is YAGOO fine already?
はいはい！あ、熱い！熱いよそこ！熱いよそれ！
Yes yes! Ah, hot! It's hot there! It's hot, that!
じゃあね、はい、じゃあグレネードを使おう、グレネード。
Well then, yes, let's use a grenade, a grenade.
うん、ししろの、いつものやつ！
Yeah, Shishiro's usual thing!
じゃあ、私がグレネードを、あの、ポイって投げるから。
Well then, I'll toss the grenade like "poy", so...
投げ、あの、投げられた反応、なんかして、面白い反応してください。
throw, um, do a reaction to being thrown, do some funny reaction.
それは私が投げたやつがオマルのとこに行ったっていうて...
That means the one I threw went over to Omaru's place...
おもしろいっていうかさ、死ぬやん。
Funny or whatever, you'd die.
いや、大丈夫大丈夫！死なない死なない。ちょっとダメージ受けるだけ、受けるだけ。ヒットポイント30ぐらいだったら大丈夫。
Nah, it's fine, it's fine! You won't die. You just take a little damage. If it's around 30 HP, it's fine.
え、わかったじゃあ。いける？
Eh, I see then. Can you do it?
ポルカ、やるよ。じゃあ、「カーン」って言ったら「ポイ」って言うね。
Polka, I'll do it. So when I say "clang", you say "poy", okay?
行けたるところからだよ？うん。
From wherever you can make it, okay? Yeah.
ポイ！うわっ！
Poy! Whoa!
どん！どーん！どーん！
Boom! Boom! Boom!
ああー！無理！もうなん、な、あ、死ぬ！
Aah! No way! What, n-, ah, I'm gonna die!
助けて！ごくし、ごくし助けて！あー、あー！
Help me! Gokushi, gokushi, help! Ah, ah!
あ、YAGOO？YAGOOふざけんなよ！
Ah, YAGOO? YAGOO, are you kidding me?!
じいさんの社長に頼るな！
Don't rely on the old man president!
見えてないし、なんか、こいつ、YAGOO埋まっとるし。
I can't even see, and somehow this guy, YAGOO is buried in here.
おいYAGOO立てよお前！もうやだ、あ、ごくしが、浮かんできてる！あ、あれが、あれがネネせ...
Hey YAGOO, get up, you! No more, ah, Gokushi is floating up! Ah, that is, that is Nene-se...
あれがラミせ... あれがししろせ... こっちは星になっちゃったわ。ごくし星の三角ボス。すごい。浮かんでる。すごい。
That is Rami-se... That is Shishiro-se... Over here I became a star. Gokushi star's triangle boss. Amazing. Floating. Amazing.
はい！かんかんかんかん！起きちゃって起きちゃって起きちゃって！朝だよ！起きちゃって！
Yes! Clang clang clang clang! Wake up, wake up, wake up! It's morning! Wake up!
起きて起きて！はい、どうしたの？
Wake up, wake up! Hey, what happened?
はぁ、はぁ、どうしよう。
Haa, haa, what should I do?
大丈夫？ 今までの記憶ある？ 大丈夫？
Are you okay? Do you remember anything so far? Are you okay?
えっ なんか ないほうがいいかもしれない。
Uh, maybe it's better if I don't.
えっと デビューして
Um, we debuted...
うん。 えーっと みんなでデビューしたじゃん。
Yeah, um, we all debuted together, right?
うん。 そこから、そこ…うん。
Yeah. And from there, from there... yeah.
えっ 今日の今日の記憶でいいんだよ。
Uh, today's, today's memory is fine.
今日か。
Today?
今日は、えっと…
Today is, um...
あっ もしかして今、配信中ですか？
Ah, wait, are we streaming right now?
そうなんだ、 実は。 実はそうなの、おまる。
That's right, actually. Actually, yes, Omaru.
と いうことは、 おまるは ボケをしなければいけない時間なんだ。
Which means it's time for Omaru to play the fool.
ボケ？！
Play the fool?!
そう。 どうやって？
That's right. How?!
さあ、 おまる。 そのギャグを使って。
Now, Omaru. Use that gag.
ギャグ？！
A gag?!
ギャグが全員だったとき、どんな感じの反応をするか
When the gag is everybody's, what kind of reaction would it get?
面白くやってみてごらん。
Try doing it in a funny way.
ギャグ！ ギャグが全員だったとき…
A gag! When the gag is everybody's...
待っていないけど、 そんな… 借りてきた。
Wait, it's not here, but... borrowed...
そんなギャグが全員だったらなんてできるのか。
If those gags were everyone's, how could we even do it?
くっ、 やるんだよ。
Damn, you just gotta do it!
コメントの、 えーっと、 こさんざいんおらに力をくれ！
Chat, um, please lend your power to Kosan-Zain O-ra!
よし、 行くぞ！ お前ら、 みんなでかかるぞ！
All right, let's go! You guys, let's all take him on!
行きます、 それでは ショートコント もし、 ギャグが新人ざいんだったら…
Here we go, then, a short skit: What if the gag was a rookie zain...
いいね。 いいね。
Nice. Nice.
メンバーシップありがとうございます！ おまるざいんにようこそ！ あっ！
Thank you for the membership! Welcome to Omaru-zain! Ah!
あ、 ギャグさんですか？ あっ、 ありがとうございます！
Ah, are you Mr. Gag? Ah, thank you so much!
え？ えでも知ってますよ、 この人。 うちスタンプで、 これギャグいるんでそもそも。
Huh? Eh, but I know this person. We have a stamp of this guy as a gag in the first place.
あっ、 え？ すごいですね、 ギャグ、 あ…え？
Ah, eh? That's amazing, a gag, ah... eh?
ギャグ、 うちのざいんになったん？
Gag, did you become our zain?
え、 どう、 明日ゾウの、 ゾウ磨くけど、 一緒にやる？
Eh, how about tomorrow we polish the elephant, want to do it together?
え、 え？！
Eh, eh?!
あっ、 磨きや！ あっ、 お前が光るんだ！ すげえすげえすげえ！
Ah, polish it! Ah, you're shining! Amazing, amazing, amazing!
はあ、 じゃあ、 ギャグは 正面係です。
Ha, well then, Gag is in charge of the front.
あの、 これからうちの、 あ、 ありがとう！ 全自動正面に仕切らしてくれるそうです！
Um, from now on, our, ah, thank you! Apparently, he'll let us fully automate the front partition!
彼も喜んでおります！ やった！ 一緒にこれからも頑張ろうね！
He's happy too! Yay! Let's keep doing our best together from now on!
ざいんとして！
As zain!
うん、 頑張るよ！
Yeah, I'll do my best!
よし、 ありがとう！ ギャグチャンネル登録よろしくお願いします！
Alright, thanks! Please subscribe to the Gag Channel!
かんかんかんかん…
Clang clang clang...
ああ、 泣いちゃいましたね、 ちょっと。 ちょっと、 ちょっとお疲れなのかもしれない。
Ah, he started crying, a little. Maybe he's a little tired.
おでこ、 うちの刈っちゃったんで おでこ、 うちの刈っちゃったところから…
My forehead got clipped by our... from where our forehead got clipped...
よし、 もう、 次こ、 次！
Alright, next, next!
あっ、 次、 次！ あ、 次、 次！ あ、 タンタンタンだね、 タンタンタンでこう。
Ah, next, next! Ah, next, next! Ah, tantantan, right, tantantan like this.
あ、 タンタンタン取ります。
Ah, I'll take tantantan.
じゃあ、 おでがて…おで、 おで、 おで、 おで、 おで。
Well, odegate... oden, oden, oden, oden, oden.
正解だから、 おでん使おう。
Since it's the correct answer, let's use oden.
すぐね、 すぐね、 落ちちゃうんです、 これ。
It falls right away, you see.
はい、 じゃあこのおでん…
Right, so this oden...
はい、 おまる持った。
Right, Omaru is holding it.
あっ、 はい。
Ah, yes.
持ったね。 え、 それ、 ラミーの特製手作りおでん！
You're holding it. Eh, is that Lamy's special handmade oden?!
ええ？！
What?!
パポケテ？
Papokete?
ただいま。
I'm back.
え？ これ、 ポルカに？
Eh? This, for Polka?
えっ、 ラミーおでん作ってくれたの？
Eh, Lamy made oden for me?
ラミーおでん作ってくれたの？
Did Lamy make oden for me?
ラミーおでんつく…ラミーおでん…ラミーおでん作ってくれたの？
Lamy made o-den... Lamy o-den... Did Lamy make oden for me?
またワンパタンになってる、 おまる優しい。
It's becoming repetitive again, gentle Polka.
違う、 違う！ ポルカパターン、 ラミーが、 ラミーが、 こう、 こう…いける？
No, no! Polka pattern, Lamy, Lamy, like this, like this... can you?
あ、 ああ、 そうだよ、 そうだよ。
Ah, ah, that's right, that's right.
あ、 そうなんだ！ えっ、 どこら辺こだわったの？ え、 ポルカ、 だから…
Ah, is that so! Eh, what part did you obsess over? Eh, Polka, so...
ラミーに…ラミーに振ってくスタイルだね。
It's a style where you toss it to Lamy...
こんにゃくが好きなの。
I like konjac.
ええ？ あ、 いいよ、 食べてな、 食べてな！ わかった！
Eh? Ah, sure, go ahead and eat it, go ahead! Understood!
もう、 もう、 もう…ラミーのためなら皿まで食ってやる！
Already, already, already... for Lamy's sake, I'll even eat the plate!
よし、 よし、 よし、 よし、 よし…おら、 おら！
Alright, alright, alright, alright, alright... take that, take that!
うまい！ うまい！
Delicious! Delicious!
ラミーのおでん…ふう！
Lamy's oden... whew!
ラミーのおでん…うますぎる！
Lamy's oden... too delicious!
販売してくれ！
Put it on sale!
味の感想になってんじゃん、 もう！ ただ食べただけの人だよ、 それ。
That's just a review of the taste already! You're just someone who ate it.
じゃあ、 もう最後、 最後、 最後！ 最後やろう。
Well then, last, last, last! Let's do the last one.
おまる、 まだ大丈夫？ まだ大丈夫？ まだ削ってない？ 大丈夫？ まだ削ってない？
Omaru, are you still okay? Still okay? Not shaved down yet? Okay? Not shaved down yet?
まだ削ってない？ 次、 まだ削ってない？
Not shaved down yet? Next, not shaved down yet?
あったまってきちゃった！ あったまってきちゃった！ よかった！
I'm warming up! I'm warming up! Great!
はい、 おまる、 じゃあピコピコハンマーあるじゃん。
Right, Omaru, so you have a piko-piko hammer.
持って！ 任せて！
Hold it! Leave it to me!
持てるよ！
I can hold it!
じゃあ、 ここで 1つ、 ピコハンと掛けまして… ししろんと解く。
Well then, here's one: What do you compare a piko-han to? Solve it with Botan.
そのこころは…どちらも…
The answer is... both...
どっちも… 戦闘力が… 100万！
Both... combat power is... one million!
うまい！ 1日すべりプレゼントします！
Delicious! I'll present you with a whole day of slipping!
一滑りポイントはありがとうございました
Thank you for the "one slip" points!
百滑りポイントでなんか景品と交換できるようにしようか
Maybe we can make it so you can exchange 100 slip points for prizes?
百滑り？
100 slips?
頑張り、頑張り。ヘタッ
Do your best, do your best. Oh gosh...
ということで、この、このモノボケはごきげんの提供でお送りいたしました。
And with that, this comedy bit was brought to you by Gokigen.
嘘でしょ？
No way, right?
でも今までで一番良くなかった？
But wasn't that the best one yet?
あ、でもね、頑張った。
Ah, but you know, I tried my best.
頑張った
She tried her best.
そうだね、頑張った。
That's right, she tried.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
なんか、なんだかですみません、あの、ぜひまた、うちの、あの配信に遊びに来てください。
Sorry about all that... Please come visit my streams again sometime!
はい、でりゃあ！
Yep, hi-yah!
行くよ、見ててね。いやなんかうれしい。え、え、嬉しい、なんか、え、ごきげん好き。
Here I go, watch me! Man, I'm so happy.
I'm so, so happy... I love Gokigen.
もう疲れ果ててご意見がわからなくなってしまった。
I'm so exhausted I don't even know what opinions I have left.
誕生日集中してくれ！
Focus on the birthday!
お前が主役だろ、おい！頑張ってね。
You're the main character here, hey!
Do your best.
楽しんでね！
Have fun!
誕生日おめでとうってもう1回言って？
Say "Happy birthday" one more time?
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！
Congrats!
誕生日！いつもラフに返してくれてありがとう！ありがとう！
Birthday! Thank you for always responding so casually! Thank you!
頑張る！頑張ってね！
I'll do my best! Do your best!
可愛いな、可愛い。バイバイ、バイバイ！
So cute, so cute. Bye-bye, bye-bye!
行かないで、行かないで。あー、帰ってきた。あ、いいよ、大丈夫だよ。ありがとう。
Don't go, don't go. Ah, they're back.
Ah, it's fine, it's okay. Thank you.
本当に、行かない、帰ることになるの。
Seriously, don't leave me, you're really going home?
え？遊びすぎいてしまったもしれない、もしかしてポルカこれ。
Huh? Did I play around too much, maybe, Polka?
え、ど、どうなんだろう？ちょっ
Uh, h-how is it? Hold on...
あれ？あれ？もう、あ？
Huh? Huh? Already, ah?
え？時間、あ、あ、じゃああの、あ、あの、えっと、あの、何か、あ、ある、ある、あるのかな？
Huh? Time—ah, ah, well, um, um,
is there something... like, um?
何か、あの、もう、えっと、はい。
Something, um, already, um, yes.
あのー、
Um...
はい。え？あ、ぐっ、あ、は、はい、はい、はい、あ。
Yes. Eh? Ah, gu—ah, ha, yes, yes, yes, ah.
すみません、あのもう全部今頭の中空っぽになっちゃった。はい。
Sorry, my mind is completely empty right now. Yep.
ということで、えっと、なんと今日告知がございます。
So, um, today we actually have an announcement!
いやあ、すみません、なんか途中で獲物のあれを切らしてしまいましたので、ちょっともう頭が混乱してまいりましたが！告知をさせてください！どう！
Man, I'm sorry, I ran out of that "prey" halfway through, so my head got all confused, but!
Please let me make an announcement! Ta-da!
おまるポルカ誕生日記念2021！
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2021!
ちょっと時間だいぶ私あの、やってしまってもう、販売しちゃっているかもしれないです。もう申し訳ないです。えっと、こちら、えっと、
I might have taken up too much time and already put them up for sale. I'm so sorry. Um, as for this, um—
ボイス＆グッズ全セット、記念ボイス全種セット、記念グッズ3種セット、
Voice & Goods Complete Set, Commemorative Voice Complete Set,
Commemorative Goods 3-Item Set...
こちら、お母さんのこうましろ先生が描いてくれた、えっと、イラストと、とまり、あの、これポルカが無理行ったんだけど、アクリルパネルに箔押しのメッセージが入ってます！
This includes illustrations drawn by our "mom," Komashiro-sensei, and Tomari...
um, I begged for this, but the acrylic panel has a foil-stamped message!
そして、テラテラ先生によるアクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー、書き下ろしこちらもイラストが描かれているんですけど、これはイラストを使わせてもらったおまるのデザインのサーカスペナント！
And then, the acrylic keychain & stickers by Tera-tera-sensei.
These also feature newly drawn illustrations, including an Omaru-designed circus pennant using those illustrations!
はい、各グッズの画像があります。はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yep, we have images of each item. Yes, please check them out!
え、こちらが、はい、イラスト、お！なっております。こちらね、あの、全部ね、買うと特典でついてくるイラストポスター、ちなみにさっきの絵とは違うんだよね、こっちの！そして特典ボイスがついてきます。よろしくお願いします！
Um, here is—yes, the illustration, oh! It's like this. If you buy the whole set,
you get an illustration poster as a bonus—which is actually different from the previous artwork!
And it comes with a bonus voice track. Please check it out!
ほら、見て違う。あ、そして、なんか箔押しのメッセージがちょっと見えますねー。これはどうなっているのかなー？うん？あー、いや、
Look, see, it's different. Ah, also, you can see a bit of the foil-stamped message.
I wonder what that says? Hmm? Ah, man—
え？どう？あ、いい感じですか？あ、あ、ちょっとちょっと、やめてやめて！いやいや、大事だから！アップにしなくていいから大丈夫だから！
Huh? How is it? Ah, looks good? Ah, wait, wait, stop, stop!
No, no, it's precious! You don't need to zoom in, it's fine!
はい、次の、次の画像どう？こちら！これね、絶対出したかったの、ペナント！
Alright, how about the next image? Here!
This—I definitely wanted to release this, a pennant!
これ房々がついてくる。房々がイメージだけどわかんない、これから房々なくなったらどうしよう。房々がついてる下に、この、ご、五角形？って言うのかな、これを
It comes with tassels. It has tassels in the image, but I don't know,
what if the tassels disappear later? Underneath the tassels, there's this—penta—hexagon? What do you call it?
つけてもらえました。
They added this for me.
ありがとうございます。可愛いでしょう？ポルカわりよ。
Thank you very much. Cute, right? Polka loves it.
テラテラ先生のイラスト好きなんだ！で、こっちは、大きさ的には、えーと、21cmか、あ、21cm、210mmだね。で、高さが300mmってことは30cmです。
I love Tera-tera-sensei's illustrations!
And as for this one, in terms of size, um, about 21 cm—ah, 21 cm, 210 mm.
And the height is 300 mm, which means 30 cm.
です。あ、こっちか。
Yes. Ah, this way.
可愛いな。まあ、でもこれだけじゃなくって、どどーん！
So cute. Well, but not just this—ta-da!
晴れる、ついに晴れる。
Finally, it's finally here!
いいでしょう？いいでしょう？
It's good, isn't it? It's good, right?
これさ、玉乗ってんでしょ。
This one has a ball on it, you see.
さっきのとこは全身なかったんだけど、これちゃんと玉乗ってるようになってるから。
The previous one didn't have her whole body, but this one properly shows her on the ball.
こちらもおよろしくお願いいたします！
So this one, please look forward to it as well!
で、えっと、まあ、記念ボイスもめっちゃ頑張って撮ったんで、よろしくお願いしまーす！
And um, we also worked really hard to record the commemorative voice packs too, so please look forward to those!
ちょっとね、
We've got a bit of...
結構、あの、あんまりよそでは無いシチュエーションボイスを取ったよ。
We recorded a situational voice pack in a situation we don't usually do.
あの、ぜひ気になる人はもう、たぶんブースが立っちゃっているのでよろしくお願いしまーす！
Um, if you're curious, the booth is probably already up, so please check it out!
はーい！
Yeah!
まあ、ごきげいと一緒に本当は歌いたかったな、なんか寂しくなっちゃったな。
Well, I really wanted to sing together with Gokusei, but it got a bit lonely.
やっぱ戻ってきてもらお、今から通話ってかけられますかね？あの、無理かな。
Can I call her right now? Or is it impossible?
コラボしたいな。ちょ待って、わかった。
I want to collab. Wait, I know!
れんせーすばい、今ここで。
Let's do a cell phone call right here, right now!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
はっ！えっと、ごきげい、いでよ！
Hey, Gokusei, pick up!
ふんだーん！
Hundang!
あれ？
Huh?
はっ！だーん！
Hundang!
うわあ！
Ah!
あれ？失敗し—うわあ！
Huh? I messed up—ah!
なんだ？な、なんだ？降ってきたなんかが。なんか降ってきたけど。
What was that? Something flew out! Something flew out!
じゃないくて今はごきげい欲しんだって。
Wait, I didn't want this! I want Gokusei back!
うお、ちがう違う違う違う、ごきげい欲しあ—！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, I want Gokusei! Ah!
ごきげい、どこー！
Gokusei, where are you?
うちのどーきー！
My- my dookie!
何も見えない。
I can't see anything.
え？
Huh?
どういうことだ、これは？
What is the meaning of this?
あ！
Ah!
おれ！やった！やったごきげい！
Oh! Yay! Yay, Gokusei!
来てくれたけど、なんかみんな、ペラペラしちゃったね。
You came, but everyone just went all flustered.
まあ、いっか。このあったら1人で4人分盛り上げるぞ！
Well, whatever! From now on, let's hype it up just the four of us!
行くぜお前ら、最後の盛り上がりを見せてくれ！
Let's go, you guys! Show us the ultimate hype for the finale!
歌いまーす。
Here we go!
ふーーん！はあ！
Fuuuu—hrah!
ここ、行くぞー！
Here we go!
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, another wild ruckus.
うー！がー！
Uhh! Grr!
高らかに笑い笑えばフレンズ（フレンズ）
If we laugh loudly, we're friends.
喧嘩してすっ茶かめっ茶かしても仲良し
Even if we fight and mess things up, we're still friends.
けものはいてものけものはいない
There are beasts here, but there are no outcasts.
本当の愛はここにある
Real love is here.
ほら君も手をつないで大冒険
Come on, join hands for a grand adventure.
（ワン・ツー・スリー）
(One, Two, Three)
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, another wild ruckus.
姿かたちも十人十色だから魅かれ合うの
Appearances are as varied as ten people, ten colors, which is why we're drawn to each other.
夕暮れ空に指をそっと重ねたら
If you gently place your finger on the twilight sky,
はじめまして（はじめまして）
Nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you more.
うー！がー！
Uhh! Grr!
振り返ればあちらこちらでトラブル（トラブル）
If you turn around, trouble pops up here and there.
なんてこったい
What a mess!
てんてんバラバラちんぷんかんぷんまとまらない
Totally scattered, utterly incoherent - nothing makes sense.
けものですもの大目に見ててね
We're beasts, so please bear with us.
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone lives freely.
そう君も飾らなくて大丈夫
That's right; you don't have to dress up.
（はい どうぞ♡）
(Here you go♡)
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
From today on, please take care of me.
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔君を待っていたの
Always, with a kind smile, I've been waiting for you.
開かれた門（ゲート）夢をいっぱい語ったら
An open gate; when you tell me all your dreams,
どこまででも（どこまででも）続いてくグレートジャ―ニー
Wherever we go, the great journey continues.
Oh東へ吠えろ西へ吠えろ
Oh, howl to the east, howl to the west.
世界中に響けサファリメロディ
Let it echo around the world - the safari melody.
―Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
- Welcome to Japari Park!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, another wild ruckus.
姿かたちも十人十色だから魅かれ合うの
Appearances are as varied as ten people, ten colors, which is why we're drawn to each other.
夕暮れ空に指をそっと重ねたら
If you gently place your finger on the twilight sky,
はじめまして（はじめまして）
Nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you more.
うー！がー！
Uhh! Grr!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la,
Oh, welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 集まれ友達
La la la la la la la la, gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la,
Oh, welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 素敵な旅立ち
La la la la la la la la, dreamy departure!
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
ようこそジャパリパークへ
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, another wild ruckus.
うー！がー！
Uhh! Grr!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ 騒々し
If we laugh loudly, friends, it's a ruckus.
すっとこどっこいも十二分に彩だから
Even silliness adds plenty of color,
しっかり出会うの
so let's truly meet.
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If we gently place our fingers against the twilight sky,
はじめまして
nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you better.
うー！がー！
Uhh! Grr!
振り返ればあちらこちらでトラブル なんてこった
If you turn around, there's trouble everywhere. Oh man!
行こう 最後尾に
Let's go to the very back!
画面が映すザ・ジャパリパーク
The screen reflects the Japari Park!
ララララ...
La la la la...
集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
画面が映すザ・ジャパリパーク
The screen reflects the Japari Park!
ララララ...
La la la la...
素敵な旅立ち ようこそジャパリパーク
A wonderful departure, welcome to Japari Park!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
このあとのプレミア公開、見てくださーい！よろしくー！
Please check out the premiere after this! See you there!
またね、ね！あ、ね、ね、あした、がんばれー！
See you again! Oh, hey, hey, do your best tomorrow!
3D LIVE #尾丸ポルカ爆誕祭 告知アリ
[3D LIVE: #OmaruPolkaBirthdayFestival - Announcement Included]